<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Derek Kozel</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Derek Kozel</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</managingEditor><webMaster>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy; Derek Kozel</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 22:40:38 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.derekkozel.com/post/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assembling the big dish</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/assembling-the-big-dish/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 22:40:38 -0700</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/assembling-the-big-dish/</guid><description>&lt;p>This weekend myself and a coworker lifted the panels of the big dish into place.
&lt;figure>
 
 
 &lt;img src="https://www.derekkozel.com/post/assembling-the-big-dish/big_dish_partially_assembled.jpg"
 /> 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately the weight of the dish and angle of the mount means that there was a gap between the final panels.
&lt;figure>
 
 
 &lt;img src="https://www.derekkozel.com/post/assembling-the-big-dish/big_dish_gap_rear.jpg"
 /> 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tunneling web traffic over SSH</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/tunneling-web-traffic-over-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 06:24:25 -0700</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/tunneling-web-traffic-over-ssh/</guid><description>&lt;p>At times it is useful to have your web traffic originate from a remote location for testing or access to geofenced resources. During university it was very useful for accessing the library resources. At other times being able to have all traffic encrypted from a laptop to a remote location such as when on an unsecured WiFi network. I&amp;rsquo;ve used this a good number of times so here is the minimal steps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic quadcopter build</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/basic-quadcopter-build/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 06:19:21 -0700</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/basic-quadcopter-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>A long term desire of mine has been to build a multicopter. Three years ago I tried flying a model powered glider and it went like a stone in a pool. In hindsight a glider is very good at catching any breeze so was a poor choice for a beginner as it was pushed far away before I could get a grip on controlling it. a few trees and almost a window later it was put in a closet then given to Goodwill. A multicopter has a much shorter flight time, but far lower wind load and can be held stationary with little effort even without fancy additions like GPS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pelco Pan Tilt head</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/pelco-pan-tilt-head/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 06:18:48 -0700</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/pelco-pan-tilt-head/</guid><description>&lt;p>For some time I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a setup for receiving from, and eventually transmitting to, satellites and other moving aerial targets such as high altitude balloons. The initial design was based off of the work done by the &lt;a href="https://satnogs.org/">SatNOGS&lt;/a> team, but ran into reliability issues when 3D printing a revised version of the helical antenna joints. Additionally the SatNOGS design is being iterated at the moment and their rotator design wasn&amp;rsquo;t complete. In searching for alternative elevation azimuth rotator designs a few options came up:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using an OpenPGP Card</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/using-an-openpgp-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 18:21:52 +0100</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/using-an-openpgp-card/</guid><description>&lt;p>I bought an &lt;a href="http://g10code.com/p-card.html">OpenPGP card&lt;/a> earlier this year and created a new GPG key (&lt;a href="http://www.derekkozel.com/2642D337.asc">2642D337&lt;/a>) during IETF 89. I’ve been using that key to sign git commits, ssh, and sign/encrypt significant emails and files. However I locked the card on purpose while experimenting with it and then encountered problems unlocking and reloading it. Since then the card has been taking up space in my wallet. Yesterday I was lounging and decided to look at my GPG setup and get the card working.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Latex in Octopress</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/latex-in-octopress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 02:21:23 +0100</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/latex-in-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many of the topics I work with involve math left, right, and center. Being able to use $$\LaTeX$$ is a big feature for me so here&amp;rsquo;s the solution I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with so far. Credit certainly goes to &lt;a href="http://drz.ac/2013/01/03/blogging-with-math/">Dr Zac&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.idryman.org/blog/2012/03/10/writing-math-equations-on-octopress/">Felix&lt;/a> for their work getting Latex playing nice. I believe that Zac&amp;rsquo;s is the more correct solution given its use of the custom header file rather than modifying the default layout. However Felix has the fix for a bug in MathJax which otherwise turns the entire page white when viewing an equation&amp;rsquo;s source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Bankruptcy</title><link>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/project-bankruptcy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 01:37:26 +0100</pubDate><author>dkozel@bitstovolts.com (Derek Kozel)</author><guid>https://www.derekkozel.com/post/project-bankruptcy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most engineers, and probably most people in general, will be familiar with how projects and tasks accumulate. Finishing university and moving three times in two months has pushed my todo list past the end of the page. I sat down today and wrote down everything I could think of that I wished, or was obliged, to accomplish in the next month and have to admit that some (many) of the project ideas that float through my head simply aren&amp;rsquo;t going to get done.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>